So we are now ready to define
我们现在准备定义
Bayes networks in a more general way.
贝叶斯网络 以更加通用的方式进行定义
Bayes networks define probability distributions over graphs of random variables.
贝叶斯网络根据随机变量的图形定义概率分布
Here's an example of a graph of
这是五个随机变量图形的例子
five variables and this Bayes network
这个贝叶斯网络
defines the distribution over those five random variables.
根据这五个随机变量定义了分布
Instead of enumerating all possibilities of combinations of these five random variables,
贝叶斯网络不是列举五个随机变量的所有组合情况
the Bayes network is defined by
而是通过每个单独节点内在的
probability distributions that are inherent to each individual node.
概率分布进行定义
For node A and B we just have a distribution,
对于节点 A 和 B 我们只得到一个分布
P(A) and P(B) because A and B have no incoming arcs.
P(A) 和 P(B) 因为 A 和 B 没有连接的弧线
C is defined as a condition distribution,
C 定义为条件分布
conditioned on A and B.
前提条件是 A 和 B
And D and E are conditioned on C.
D 和 E 取决于 C
The joint probability represented by a Bayes network is
通过贝叶斯网络展现的联合概率
the product of various Bayes network probabilities
是贝叶斯网络各种概率的乘积
that are defined over individual nodes,
单个节点定义了这些概率
but each node's probability is only conditioned on the incoming arcs.
但是每个节点的概率只依赖于连接的弧线
So A has no incoming arc,
A 没有连接的弧线
therefore we just want the probability of A.
所以我们只得到 P(A)
C has two incoming arcs,
C 有两条连接的弧线
so if we define the probability of C conditioned A and B.
如果我们定义 P(C|A, B)
And D and E have one incoming arc as shown over here.
如图所示 D 和 E 各有一条连接的弧线
The definition of this joint distribution by using
使用下面这些因子定义这个联合分布
the following factors has one really big advantage.
具有一个非常大的优势
Whereas the joint distribution over any five variables
鉴于任意五个变量的联合分布
requires two to the five minus one which is 31 probability values.
需要 2 的五次方 减去 1 即 31 个概率值
The Bayes network over here only requires 10 such values P(A)
这里贝叶斯网络只需要 10 个概率值
specific of one value from which we can derive P of not A, same for P(B).
P(A) 只需要一个数值 还可以得出 P(﹁A) P(B)也是这样
P (C) given AB is derived by a distribution over
P(C|A, B) 等于 C
C conditioned on any combination of A and B of which there are four if A and B is binary.
依赖于 A 和 B 组合的不同情况 如果 A 和 B 是二元关系 会有四种情况
P(D) given C has two parameters.
P(D|C) 会有两个参数
For P(D) given C and P(D) given not C and the
即 P(D|C) 和 P(D|﹁C)
same is true for P(E) given C. So if you add those up,
P(E|C) 也是如此 那么把这些情况汇总起来
you get 10 parameters in total.
总共得到 10 个参数
So the compactness of the Bayes network leads to a representation that's clearly
贝叶斯网络的严密性可以
significantly better to large networks than
更好更清晰地展现大型网络
the combinatorial approach which goes to all combinations of variable values.
这与组合方法对不同变量值进行组合形成对比
That is a key advantage of Bayes networks and that is the reason that Bayes networks
这是贝叶斯网络的主要优势 也说明了贝叶斯网络
have been used so extensively for all kinds of problems.
广泛应用在各种问题中的原因
So here's a quiz.
这里有个测试
So how many probability values are required to specify this Bayes network?
需要多少个概率值指定这个贝叶斯网络呢？
Please put your answer on the wall.
请输入答案